

JOHN ZHAO

Location: Los Gatos, CA 95032 Email: <u>john.zhao@sunvalle.net</u> Contact: 408-621-2926

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

More than 29 years of hands-on experiences in computing System, Application, Networking, Security and programming environments, lead large-scale technical projects, working with internal staff and vendors to define requirements, scope technical efforts, determine solutions, and then implement those solutions. Expert technical skills in UNIX/Linux Systems/Application build/support and development large DC on-prem/Cloud VPC integration laaS, PaaS, laC, docker/Jenkins /k8s CI/CD/Automation with Terraform/Ansible on KVM/AWS/GCP/Azure, Python(OS/System/DB/Web Interfaces/networking/automation/data science integration, Critial data encryption/recovery, Hard-working, good team management, self-motivated, well-organized and able to work effectively under pressure on demanding environment.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

GitLab / GitHub / Jenkins / CI / CD/ Cloudformation /Terraform / Ansible, Kubernetes / Docker, UNIX / Linux /Windows/MacOS/WinAD-SFU, Oracle / MySQL / SQL, LDAP / KDC / NIS / IPA, SAN / NAS/Transparent Proxy, Strong Bash Shell Scripting with C/C++ / Python Package management, J2SE / J2EE /Apache / TLS, SQL / PL / SQL, Jumpstart / Kickstart / KVM, Grafana / Splunk /Data Dog/ Dynatrace

HOBBY & INTEREST

Classical Guitar | HiFi Audio

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION AND CERTIFICATION:

- Southeast University, China B.E. Electromagnetism Field & Microwave 1986-1990
- San Diego State University, California USA B.S. Computer Science 1992-1996
- Caltech Post Graduate Program in DevOps 2022 Mar-Dec

Other: Singapore Citizen | US Green Card holder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sunvalley Computer Inc. (02/1999 to present) System Software Engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps Bay Area, California, United States & Singapore

- Invented Zero Trust DevOps Automation (High secure Crytocurrency level)
- System Software Engineer Lead SRE/DevOps/IT Engineering consulting for US custormer
- Unix/Linux/DB security audit, migration & data recovery over on-Prem and cloud
- C++/Python, AI, Data science, ETL/Pyspark, docker-compose, ldap/Kerberos, RestApi, Oauth on Dev & Jenkins, K8s, Java, TDV AWS, Azure DataLake, AAD, next.js,nodejs, AWS cli, terraform, ansible CI/CD on DevOps



Consulting supported Clients: Sun Mirosystems, NUS/NTU Com Center, Agilent, NEC, Visa Internationl, DBS Vickers, Orange(French Telecom), Converge Asia, Trend Micro, Polaris Wireless E911, Walmat Labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, FormFactor, Trident Microsystems, HGST, Oracle Cloud, Kroger, Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

07/1996 – 10/2001: Sun Microsystems Inc: System Software Engineer & Professional service with Singapore & US project

05/2004 – 09/2006: VISA International: Solaris Engineer: with APAC credit services transaction regional deployment

07/2006 - 03/2008: FormFactor Inc: Systems Analyst: building Oracle ERP with Sun Microsystems, Oracle & NetApp SAN/NAS, incharge UNIX/Linux/Storage related platform & services

10/2008 – 02/2011: Trident Microsystems: UNIX Engineer Architect creating enginnering services between Santa Clara/Munich with high security, incharge global sorce control repo & UNIX/Linux automation

04/2011 – 11/2014: HGST: Principle Engineer: take over IBM DCE/DFS services, create AWS cloud service & Linux as solution 11/2014 – 03/2019: Principle engineer- Lead SRE/DevOps: support Walmat labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, Oracle Cloud US/UK region

04/2019 – 02/2022: Kroger: Sr Software engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps: creating ecommerce innovation platform with AWS/GKE/Azure & develop python backend services

02/2022: Principle engineer – Lead SRE: Data platform services automation, python, data lake, terradata, Fintech securities support Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

Advanced Network Technology Laboratories Pte Ltd (11/2001 to 05/2004) Regional Tech Support (Linux networking & security product after sales) Singapore

- APAC regional technical support for ISP customer (Linux based networking & security product)
- Remote system upgrade & License activate over SSH tunnel

Ascom Technologies (06/1995 to 02/1999) **Tech Support (Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider)**Singapore

- Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider (Software from UK, Mainfrain Hardware from USA)
- ProC, UNIX/HP-UX/Solaris systems, security & databases services

REFERENCE (Available on request)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-j-zhao-8656698/

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/0bf53df1d328/